edfinancial.com 2010-05-23

# Edfinancial Services - Student Loan Services - Servicing Federal and Private Student Loans

At Edfinancial Services, we continue to develop technological enhancements for students, families, schools and our partners. We are committed to excellence in customer service, and your privacy is important to us. This policy is effective on January 5, 2006. 

### TRUSTe Privacy Program

Edfinancial Services is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. The information contained in this policy is applicable to Edfinancial Services. This privacy statement covers [www.Edfinancial.com](http://www.edfinancial.com/ "Edfinancial Services - servicing federal and private student loans"). Because Edfinancial Services wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users’ privacy, we have agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact [info@edfinancial.com](mailto:info@edfinancial.com). If they do not receive acknowledgment of their inquiry or their inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, they should then contact TRUSTe through the [TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php "TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process"). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve users concerns.

### What this Privacy Policy Covers

This Privacy Statement applies to Edfinancial Services and governs data collection and usage at all Edfinancial Services sites and services such as [www.Edfinancial.com](http://www.edfinancial.com/ "Edfinancial Services - servicing federal and private student loans").

Edfinancial Services is a servicer of student loans and provides various online services for other providers of educational funding. You may access some services provided by Edfinancial Services with pages that are co-branded through the site of one of our partner lenders. It is important to note that this privacy policy does not apply to other areas of that lender's site that are not provided by Edfinancial Services.

Some areas of our websites may provide links to non-Edfinancial Services sites. If you link to a site that is not an Edfinancial Services website, the privacy policy of that site and its terms of Use of use apply to you. We encourage you to learn about the privacy policy of any third party before giving personal information to them.

### Use of Personal Identifying Information

Edfinancial Services does not collect any nonpublic personal information from visitors to our sites unless you expressly provide it to us through one of our online services. Edfinancial Services does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. If you choose to register on an Edfinancial Services website in order to utilize an online service that requires you to log in, Edfinancial Services will collect basic information such as name, email address and brief demographic information. If you choose to submit an online loan application, Edfinancial Services will collect information such as your Social Security Number, and that of your endorser or co-borrower, if applicable, date of birth, driver's license number, phone number, and references required for the completion of a student loan application.  If you choose to select a lender that is not serviced by Edfinancial Services and wish your request to be submitted to your school,  Edfinancial Services will collect information such as the borrower and/or student name, phone number and e-mail address and the lender name, code and phone number.  Edfinancial Services will store this information for six (6) months for purposes of research, resend requests, and to send via batch to your school.

We currently contract with several online partners to help manage and optimize our Internet business and communications. We use the services of a marketing company to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our site. To do this, we use Web beacons and cookies provided by our marketing company on this site. The type of information we collect includes, pages visited, product, school and lender codes, IP address, the type of browser you are using, the websites you visit immediately before and immediately after you visit our websites, and other anonymous data involving your use of our websites. By supplementing our records, this information helps us learn things like what pages are most attractive to our visitors, which of our products most interest our customers, and what kinds of offers our customers like to see. Although our marketing company logs the information coming from our site on our behalf, we control how that data may and may not be used.

Edfinancial Services enables you to voluntarily provide personal information to third parties such as college or university admissions departments. This information will not be provided by Edfinancial Services to any third party other than the colleges or universities that you select. The selected university will be communicating with you, and the university's use of your data is governed by its privacy policy.

If you elect to use our referral service for informing a friend about one of our sites, Edfinancial Services will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting them to view the article that you are sending them. Edfinancial Services does not store this information, and it is for the sole purpose of sending the one-time email.

If you choose not to uncheck the Newsletter box on your registration form, you agree that Edfinancial Services may periodically send you an e-mail newsletter which includes educational or marketing information to the email address with which you registered. If you choose not to uncheck the Offers box on your registration form, you agree that Edfinancial Services or Edamerica, Inc. may periodically send educational or marketing information to the email address with which you registered.  You may unsubscribe to either service at any time in the newsletter or registration areas of the sites or by visiting [our login manager](https://loans.edfinancial.com/LoginApp/Default.aspx "Edfinancial Services - servicing federal and private student loans"). After logging into your account, select edit my account information.  You may then opt out of the Newsletter or Offers by unchecking the appropriate box.  If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may also opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication.  You may also contact us for assistance at [info@edfinancial.com](mailto:info@edfinancial.com) or by calling 1-800-337-6884. You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

Certain processes, such as online loan applications, will require that you provide your social security number and date of birth if you choose to continue with the online process. Once this information is provided, it will be associated by Edfinancial Services with the user account that is then logged on, and you will not need to provide it again. Thereafter, you will only need your username and password to access your account information or to complete forms in other processes. For your security, the social security number that you enter cannot be used with any other account.

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law where in we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

### Minimum Age Requirement

By law, Edfinancial Services cannot collect any information from persons who are not yet 13 years of age. If you are under 13 years of age, you can utilize the information provided in many areas of our site, but you are not authorized to create an account.

### Updating Personal Information

You may update or modify basic personal information associated with your account. [Our login manager](https://loans.edfinancial.com/LoginApp/Default.aspx) allows you to update basic data regarding your account.

### Use of Cookies

If you choose to register with the Edfinancial Services Sites in order to utilize a service that requires you to log in, your user ID will be stored in a temporary "cookie" on your web browser. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server to help us identify you. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. The cookie that manages your login will be removed as soon as you close your browser. Other cookies that are used are for customization of content and contain no personally identifying information. Our cookies are not used to collect any nonpublic personal information. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

### Website Use Information

Web servers at Edfinancial Services automatically recognize your domain name, but not your e-mail address. No nonpublic personal information is collected unless you choose to provide it to us through one of our online services. Our web server does collect information such as domain name, number of hits, pages visited and length of user session in order to compile website statistics that enable us to analyze how our websites are used. This information is then used to improve the usefulness of the sites.

### Confidentiality and Security

The security of your personal information is important to us.  When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).  [To learn more about SSL, visit <http://info.ssl.com/article.aspx?id=10241>.]

In addition to the use of SSL technology, we follow industry accepted best practices for protecting personal information; both during transmission and at rest on our systems. While no method of communication over the Internet, or electronic storage is ever 100% secure; we have gone to great lengths to protect your personal information through the use of layered firewalls, intrusion detection/protection systems, file level encryption of data while at rest and encryption of data while in transit over our network. All systems provide extensive logging and automated reporting of issues enabling timely response, interdiction and corrective actions if necessary.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can email us at [info@edfinancial.com](mailto:info@edfinancial.com).

### Passwords

There is a link available on the [Edfinancial Services log-in page](http://loans.edfinancial.com/LoginApp/Default.aspx) to enable you to change your password at any time.

If you forget your password, there is a link on the log-in page that will enable you to enter your Username or Email address with which you originally registered. When you submit this information, if your information matches what Edfinancial Services has recorded for you, your username and password will be emailed to you.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Edfinancial Services may occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect company and customer feedback. We encourage you to periodically review this Policy to be informed of how Edfinancial Services is protecting your information. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days.

### Contact information

If you have any questions about this policy please contact:

Customer Privacy  
Edfinancial Services  
120 North Seven Oaks Drive  
Knoxville, TN 37922  
1-800-337-6884 or [info@edfinancial.com](mailto:info@edfinancial.com)

### California Privacy

If you are resident of California, “Your Privacy Rights” allow you to receive an Information-Sharing Disclosure. This disclosure provides a list of categories of personal information shared, during the immediately preceding calendar year, with other businesses for their direct marketing purposes, and the names and addresses of other businesses with whom such information was shared. You may request this disclosure by contacting us at the information provided above.

We will respond to requests made to the designated contact point and provide the Information-Sharing Disclosure within 30 days of receipt of request.

If your request is made to an address, other than the one provided in this policy, the Information-Sharing Disclosure will be responded to in a “reasonable time period,” no later than 150 days from receipt of the request.

For more information, visit the [California Privacy homepage](http://www.privacy.ca.gov/ "California privacy").
